# Sam Protsenko

Software Developer

84333, Ukraine, Kramatorsk Kirilkina st. 26/61  $^{(2)}$  +3 8 097 5277313  $\bullet$  8 (06264) 6-70-10  $\bullet$  joe.skb7@gmail.com



## Personal Information

Date of Birth June 5, 1987

Place of Birth Kramatorsk, Ukraine

Nationality Ukraininan
Marital Status Single

## Summary

Motivated software engineer with experience in crossplatform development and deploying with Qt, pure C and C++.

Good knowledge of assident tools such as Git, Doxygen, Valgrind etc.

Familiarity with Linux system, utilities, Bash scripting.

Glad to extend my knowledge in these areas and also to acquire new ones.

Interested in moving to Kiev for a full time job.

#### Education

2010-2010 **Diploma mill**, "INTUIT" Internet University, Distance education.

 $\textit{Subject} \colon \mathsf{C}{++} \mathsf{\ programming}$ 

Certificate: http://www.intuit.ru/diplom/ADYGaySyhoFA/A00091223/

2008–2009 Specialist, Donbas State Mechanical Engineering Academy, Kramatorsk.

Speciality: Automation of technological processes

Thesis Subject: Designing and building of electric drive with frequency control for stock damper

test bench.

2004–2008 Bachalor, Donbas State Mechanical Engineering Academy, Kramatorsk.

Speciality: Automation of technological processes

## Experience

2009–Present **Software Developer**, *AlterEGO*, Kramatorsk.

Design and coding of crossplatform software.

2007-2008 **Software Developer**, *AlterEGO*, Kramatorsk.

Design and coding of Windows software as part-time worker.

## Languages

Russian Fluent My native language
Ukrainian Fluent My native language

English Pre-intermediate Speaking, reading and writing

# Computer skills

Delphi/Pascal (not active), Objective-C (not active)

Tools Git, CMake, Doxygen, Cppcheck, Packages Maple<sup>TM</sup>, MATLAB<sup>TM</sup>, Maxima,

Valgrind, LATEX Proteus<sup>TM</sup>

Platforms Linux, MacOS<sup>TM</sup>, Windows<sup>TM</sup>, Technologies Linux API, POSIX, Carbon/Cocoa,

DOS<sup>TM</sup> WinAPI, COM

### **Publications**

2010

Software Model-View-Presenter implementation in Qt.

Development http://habrahabr.ru/blogs/qt\_software/107698/

### Other Activities

Sep 2011–Today Maintainer of "INSTEAD" Debian package. Prepared packages can be found here:

http://mentors.debian.net/packages/uploader/joe.skb7%40gmail.com

Feb 2011–Today Translator and mentor of "Qt in Education Course Material" project that available at

http://lorcode.org/wiki/Qt\_in\_Education\_Course\_Material

### Interests

Bicycling I like to ride my bike around the purlieu

Mountains Hiking at Caucasus Mountains, climbing, outdoor roaming

Guitar I've been playing electric guitar since schooldays

Music Inspired by J.S.Bach, Vivaldi, Dream Theater, Deep Purple, Pink Floyd and many others

Books Science fiction, classics and some fantasy

Electornics Guitar effects, microcontrollers, electric drives and household appliances

GNU/Linux Sometimes I fall into nocturnal research and hacking on Linux